<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: metal slug 3 | Watch out - Alien Language!]]></title>
  <link href="http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/blog/categories/metal-slug-3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-28T19:14:16+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alien Speaker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[The Humble Mobile Bundle] Quick review of Metal Slug 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/blog/2013/03/28/review-metal-slug-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T12:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/blog/2013/03/28/review-metal-slug-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://humblebundle.com"><img class="center" src="/images/humble_mobile_bundle.png" title="‘Humble Mobile Bundle’" ></a></p>

<p>I’m into charity, especially when you can do something good and you’re immediately rewarded with awesome games. In the past years the <a href="http://humblebundle.com"><strong>Humble Bundle</strong></a> began to combine the ideas of <em>pay what you want</em>, <em>drm-free</em>, <em>cross-platform</em> and <em>charity</em>  to create awesome gaming packages. The bundles are offered for a limited time, so you have to be quick if you want to pick one up.</p>

<p>A few days ago the latest bundle was released, which will be available until Tuesday, April 9th. A few of the old ideals were dropped for this one, because it’s neither cross-platform (only available for android devices) nor drm-free. But still, it offers great games for a small price, so I can still promote it without getting a bad feeling.</p>

<p>Today I want to write a little about <strong>Metal Slug 3</strong>, which is one of the games you can get with this bundle. Maybe it helps you to decide whether you should by it or not. As far as I can manage it I will write reviews for the other games, too.</p>

<!--more -->

<p><img class="center" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/–C540PUnv_Q/UVRtZigiwbI/AAAAAAAABPU/_AdT-u-y6L0/s872/2013+-+1" title="‘The opening screen’" ></p>

<p>Metal Slug 3 is a classic arcade, side-scrolling action game like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turrican"><em>Turrican</em></a>. Both graphics and game play reminds of old Nintendo Super Famicom<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> days: It’s colourful, fast paced and forces you to constantly concentrate on the screen’s action.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-TZo1iIBCGRs/UVQXkTePQlI/AAAAAAAABOc/rwtPbKgVZ7g/s872/2013+-+2" title="‘Right after game start. The crab you see is one of the first enemies you can shoot’" ></p>

<p>After starting the game you can choose between four characters. While Metal Slug 3 is an action game it’s quite impressive that you can choose between two man <em>and</em> two women for confronting the enemy. As far as I can tell it does not matter what character you pick, because they all do the some: Running, jumping and shooting in all directions.</p>

<p>That’s what the game is all about: Fight your way to the end of the level. On your way you’ll find power ups which will improve your guns for a short period of time and shoots. Sometimes there a even tanks and mechas you can ride. Both upgrades give you  more firepower and extra protections against enemy fire. But still, tanks and machas are not invulnerable: After suffering enough shots they will eventually brake and explode.</p>

<p>Remember the original <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>? Like many old side-scrolling games you can’t get back to a screen you have already passed. So be careful and think where you want to go before rushing through the levels. You may miss crossroads or secret passages, that will bring more variety to the game. If you’re going to play it a second or third time finding all these different ways will protect Metal Slug 3 for becoming boring. This level of detail is a quite cool feature of this game.</p>

<p>As you fight your way through the levels you will eventually reach the end. There the boss enemy will await you for an epic final battle. You will face a big monster with a lot of health points and aggressive weapons designed only for one thing: killing you!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-uOvArKcO5DI/UVQXkbiSj7I/AAAAAAAABOI/FbTOBfpB3Ys/s872/2013+-+1" title="‘Who’s the boss? Well, this tiny guy is at least the boss of level one’" ></p>

<p>That’s it. In other levels new enemies will await you, but the core gameplay won’t change anymore. Typically I don’t enjoy games like Metal Slug 3 much because I suck at them, but it’s quite a good time killer. It’s definitely not the worst game I ever played, even though it’s not my cup of coffee.</p>

<p>The game is entirely controlled via touch screen. On the left side of the screen you move you character while the right side provides three buttons: a <strong>big</strong> one for shooting and to small ones for throwing granades and jumping. Although there’s no tactile feedback this setup is doing a decent job. Without practice on that particular controls I seldom missed an input.</p>

<p>If you’re a fan of the mentioned side-scrolling games I think you’ll be more than happy with Metal Slug 3. And even if you’re not it’s good enough to give it a try.</p>

<p>Finally I want to point out a bug. If you try to play the game on a device that runs an “unsupported language” you might encounter the problem that no texts are displayed but “error loading”. In my case it was <em>German</em> that triggered the bug, but there might be more languages Metal Slug 3 is not able to speak.</p>

<p>According to the comments on Google Play this is an old and know problem, but it seems the developers are not going to fix it. Well, there is a workaround: Change the system language to “English” before launching the game and it will work correctly. That’s not user-friendly, but I can life with that solution. And because I’m lazy my Nexus 7 constantly speaks English with me now, which supports my infinite quest to master this language.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-afRUESR0YWM/UVRvUgqZSeI/AAAAAAAABP4/2MP62PWZx7Q/s872/28.03.13+-+1" title="‘error loading when your system language ist alien to the game’" ></p>

<p>Happy Gaming!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>My usual call for help</strong></p>

<p><small>Although I hope you enjoy reading my articles I have to ask for your help. English is not my native language and the sole purpose of this blog is to improve it. If you find a typo, incorrect grammar or bad style please let me know. Use the comments below or send me an <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#097;&#108;&#105;&#101;&#110;&#064;&#115;&#116;&#111;&#110;&#101;&#100;&#103;&#111;&#108;&#101;&#109;&#046;&#100;&#101;">email</a> with my mistakes. Without getting notified about what I made wrong I won’t be able to improve my language skills.</small></p>

<p><small>Thanks for considering to contribute to my little quest.</small></p>

<hr />
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><small>at least in Germany better know as “Super Nintendo Entertainment System” (SNES)</small><a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
