<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Watch out - Alien Language!]]></title>

  &#8230;

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[a new beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/blog/2013/03/27/a-new-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T20:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stonedgolem.github.com/alienlanguage/blog/2013/03/27/a-new-beginning</id>
    
    












    <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fstonedgolem.github.com%2Falienlanguage%2Fblog%2F2013%2F03%2F27%2Fa-new-beginning%2F&amp;user_id=stonedgolem&amp;title=a+new+beginning&amp;category=text&amp;description=&amp;tags=" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
      <p>Here it is. The Beginning of a new blog. For the first time in my life I’m starting to write long texts in English – and I’m crazy enough to publish the result on the internet for everyone to see. I do this because English is not my native language. It’s somehow alien to me although I’m not a beginner in this tongue. A decade ago my English was better<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> but as soon as I entered university I did not used my language skills actively. I read a few books in English – but talking? No way! As time passes my tongue got old and rusty and I began to stumble because I had to search for words I once knew.</p>

<p>So I found myself on a crossroad with two ways to go on: Surrender to fate, do nothing, and wait until the rust turns to dust. <strong>Or</strong> I could get my ass up and do something against the degeneration. As you can see I choose the active path, set up a blog, which forces me to write<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> in English. I make it public for two reasons:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>If you do something in public then you have in interest to continue that work because everyone would know if you fail. So regular updates are more likely when the public is watching.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I depend on feedback for reaching my goal of better English. Anyone who finds a typo or wrong grammar or bad style is invited to contact <em>and</em> correct me! Whether per comment or <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#097;&#108;&#105;&#101;&#110;&#064;&#115;&#116;&#111;&#110;&#101;&#100;&#103;&#111;&#108;&#101;&#109;&#046;&#100;&#101;">email</a>. Without getting noticed of mistakes I would constantly repeat them and the time I spend writing this blog would be useless. So please get in contact if you see something I made wrong!</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Well, I might (or better: <em>will</em>) get a lot of spam by publishing my email on the internet, but that’s okay as long as <em>their</em> English is less eloquent than mine. Thank god I still have the opportunity to get rid of that address if the level of spam gets to high. When I should be forced to change it, you’ll be among the first who will be informed!</p>

<p>Before ending this post I would like to thank <a href="http://octopress.org">OctoPress</a> and <a href="http://guthub.com">github</a> fore providing the infrastructure of this blog. Moreover thanks to the developers of ReText (the editor I use to edit my posts) and Markdown (the markup language which simplified my life a lot). And thanks to all the people who step by, take a look and leave a comment.</p>

<p>So, that’s it. That’s the beginning and the first post. Time for some more exciting content!</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>or at least I <em>remember</em> it to be better. In retrospective I think I did all the things well I’ve done back then.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>and <em>think</em>, for it makes writing a text of more than three sentences far easier!<a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

    ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
